<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>OGD Handbook - Identify</title><link href="//opendata-swiss.github.io/ogd-handbook-site/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//opendata-swiss.github.io/ogd-handbook-site/feeds/identify.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//opendata-swiss.github.io/ogd-handbook-site/</id><updated>2016-06-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>What is Open Government Data (OGD)?</title><link href="//opendata-swiss.github.io/ogd-handbook-site/identify/opengovdata.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-26T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-06-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Open Government Data Switzerland</name></author><id>tag:opendata-swiss.github.io,2016-06-26:/ogd-handbook-site/identify/opengovdata.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open Government Data is data from the public administration that is made available for secondary use by anyone interested, free of charge and ideally in machine-readable form. The Swiss OGD portal opendata.swiss contains a wide range of datasets including communal boundaries in Switzerland, population statistics, current weather data, historical documents and a directory of Swiss literature. The data are often made available as complete datasets which can be reused or combined by users to create applications and visualizations that reveal new connections between existing data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many data are already available free of charge, but are not identified as OGD. Such data are especially suitable for publication on opendata.swiss, as they can be linked on the portal without much additional effort being required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further information on OGD can be found on the following sites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.egovernment.ch/en/umsetzung/e-government-schweiz-2008-2015/open-government-data-schweiz/"&gt;OGD Strategy for Switzerland 2014-2018&lt;/a&gt; defines objectives and measures for implementing OGD at the federal level. The strategy also forms the basis for cooperation with cantons and communes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailed information on OGD is offered by the internationally recognized &lt;a href="http://okfn.org"&gt;Open Knowledge International&lt;/a&gt;. The Foundation’s Swiss section is the &lt;a href="http://opendata.ch"&gt;Opendata.ch association&lt;/a&gt;, which organizes events for users and those interested in OGD and represents the OGD community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Benefit from existing knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many organizations already publish data as OGD. You can benefit from their experience or even work with them. The Federal Archives will be happy to assist you. &lt;a href="mailto:opendata@bar.admin.ch"&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to consult potential data users, such as journalists, programmers or &lt;a href="http://opendata.ch"&gt;Opendata.ch&lt;/a&gt;, at an early stage. In this way you can find out which datasets are most in demand.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>What data does my organization hold?</title><link href="//opendata-swiss.github.io/ogd-handbook-site/identify/identifying.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-06-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Open Government Data Switzerland</name></author><id>tag:opendata-swiss.github.io,2016-06-25:/ogd-handbook-site/identify/identifying.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In order to publish OGD, you need to know what data your organization holds. Ideally, you will have an inventory of all datasets in your organization. However, this is not absolutely necessary. Start by identifying just the datasets that are most often requested and may already have been published. If you wish to compile a complete inventory of your data collections afterwards, you can find further information here.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Identifying OGD: list of questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following questions will help you to identify data that can be published on opendata.swiss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which data have already been published (website, other portals, etc.)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which data are most often requested within your organization? Would it be feasible to publish them proactively?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which data in your organization should be published for reasons of efficiency (one-off publication rather than repeated individual delivery)?  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you have a complete overview of your data collections (inventory)?  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is information about your datasets available through other IT data gathering?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have identified suitable data, you must establish whether it is technically and legally possible to release them. Further information on preparing data for publication can be found in the &lt;a href="/en/category/prepare"&gt;“Prepare” section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Distinguishing between OGD and services for specific customers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the data published as OGD are those for which there is wide demand and which can be reused by a number of people. By contrast, datasets that were created in response to a specific customer request do not normally constitute OGD. Further information on this distinction can be &lt;a href="/en/library/bericht-abgrenzung-leistungen"&gt;found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Compiling a data inventory</title><link href="//opendata-swiss.github.io/ogd-handbook-site/identify/inventory.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-06-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Open Government Data Switzerland</name></author><id>tag:opendata-swiss.github.io,2016-06-24:/ogd-handbook-site/identify/inventory.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Depending on the size of your organization, compiling an inventory of your data is a recommended tool for publishing OGD but not a requirement. A data inventory gives you an overview of the available data and makes it easier to identify those that are suitable for OGD. However, there is no reason not to publish individual datasets on opendata.swiss.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;Situation at the federal level&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OGD Strategy for Switzerland 2014-2018 gives the Confederation the following task:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M4 Setting up an inventory of the Confederation’s datasets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A central directory of Federal Administration datasets which are appropriate for OGD should gradually be drawn up and published. This inventory is a basis for further development and planning of the OGD offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Archives coordinate this central directory, which is to contain information about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data fonds in the form of databases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;registers (data warehouses)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;similar collections of structured datasets.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Archives have already conducted a first round of inventorization and &lt;a href="/en/library/bericht-datenbestaende-bund"&gt;documented it here&lt;/a&gt;. The second round is scheduled for autumn 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of countries have already accumulated more experience with data inventorization:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://data.gov.uk/data/search"&gt;UK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://project-open-data.cio.gov/implementation-guide"&gt;USA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openstate.eu/en/2014/10/government-wide-data-inventory-ready-in-spring-2015/"&gt;Netherlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry></feed>